tympanus.net 2017-02-01

# Privacy Policy

At tympanus.net, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information that is received and collected by tympanus.net and how it is used.

**If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us[by email](mailto:info@tympanus.net).**

## Log Files

Like many other web sites, tympanus.net makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes **internet protocol (IP) address** , **type of browser** , **Internet Service Provider (ISP)** , **date/timestamp** , **referring/exit pages** , and **number of clicks** to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information can be linked to information that is personally identifiable (i.e. when you comment or contact us via one of our forms and leave your name/email).

## Cookies

On tympanus.net several third-party cookies are used, such as the ones of Google Analytics and social networks.  
Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web bugs on our site. Our advertising partners include [BuySellAds.com](http://buysellads.com/).

## Third-party ad servers

Third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on tympanus.net send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web bugs) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

_tympanus.net has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers._

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices, as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. tympanus.net’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

**If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options.** More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.
